# 大家好 前兩天去了一下兄弟家
Hi everyone! I visited my buddy a couple of days ago.
# 你看 他家又有一點點蜂蜜了
Look! He has some honey again.
# 哇 好香啊 他這種蜂蜜
Wa! It smells so good, this kind of honey.
# 你看 前兩天 前兩天有點冷
Look! A couple of days ago, it was a bit cold a couple of days ago.
# 現在就結成這樣子了
So the honey has already crystallized.
# 稠稠的
It's rather thick.
# 嗯~
Um~
# 好香啊 這個
It smells really good!
# 現在都
It has already,
# 結晶啦 結成這樣子啦
crystallized. You can see the crystals.
# 可以哦 像是
Not bad. It's like,
# 像有沙的一樣
like, there's some sand.
# 現在是 已經是春蜜了 現在
It's now, it's already spring honey now.
# 不過老是下雨 產量不高
But the yield is not that high, as it's always raining.
# 只有一點點
There's just a tiny little bit.
# 去搞一隻雞來烤
Let me get a chicken and grill it.
# 蜜汁小雞
Honey-grilled chicken.
# 先把它放好
Let me store it well first.
# 嘿嘿 抓到了
Hehe. I got it!
# 你看 那麼小的
Look! It's so tiny.
# 它頭上還有一坨毛的
There's a bunch of hair on it's head.
# 你看
Look!
# 到下面去烤
Let me take it down there and grill it.
# 應該兩斤多到三斤
I think it should be a kilogram to a kilo and a half.
# 已經把它抓下來了
So I've caught it and taken it here.
# 給它近 給它的近距離看一下
Let's give you a close, a close up so that you have can a look.
# 剛才它跑得太快了
It was just running too fast.
# 要不要
You want it?
Do you?
# 你看這撮毛
Have a look at the hair here!
# 立起來的哦
It's standing.
# 好少呀 這隻
It's a small chicken.
# 兩斤多
A bit more than a kilogram
# 你看這個雞
Have a look at the chicken!
# 你看 頭髮上 它還梳了中分哦
Look! Its's hair is central-parting.
# 立起來這裡
And it's standing here.
# 用來烤
Let's grill it.
# 全身都沒甚麼肥肉的
There's hardly any fat all over the body.
# 它的爪子
Its foot.
# 好 我燒點水來
Alright! Let me boil some water.
# 你看
Look!
# 把它搞定啦
Everything is ready.
# 雖然個子小 但是
It's small, but
# 很多肉哦
it's really meaty.
# 還出來一個皇冠在這裡
It even has a crown here.
# 我把它 去一下內臟
Let me, clean up the guts.
# 把內臟去一下
Let me clean up the guts.
# 雞屁股 給你吃
The butt is yours.
# 先把這些 肉 割一下哦
Let me, here, skin, slice it a few times first.
# 這樣子更入味
Then it will be more flavourful.
# 誒呀 這把刀 那麼鈍
Eh? This knife is so blunt.
# 這個雞腿要割一下下 (註︰「一下下」甚麼意思？)
The chicken leg needs to be sliced a few times.
# 割幾下的話就
With a few slices,
# 鹽吶
the salt, and ah...
# 全部都把它弄進裡面去
Everything can get inside.
# 這個雞放到裡面去 別被那個小狗搞掉啦
Let me put the chicken inside. I'm not gonna let the dogs take it.
# 你看 加點生薑
Look! Put some ginger.
# 這鮮 鮮薑
It's fresh, fresh ginger.
# 能去掉它的那個
It can remove the,
# 身上的味道
the odour on its body.
# 就沒那麼腥
So that it won't smell too bloody.
# 再加點鹽
Then put some salt.
# 鹽 沒甚麼味道
The salt, doesn't smell anything.
# 鹽要搞多一點
We need a little bit more salt.
# 加了鹽 加點這個
With some salt, we can put some, you know,
# 醬油
some soy sauce.
# 沒有醬油了呀
No more soy sauce?
# 剛剛好夠
Just enough.
# 有點這個 料酒
Put some, well, cooking wine.
# 加點料酒
Put some cooking wine.
# 再搞點那個油
Put put some, some oil.
# 不搞點油的話 等下很那個的
Without some oil, it would be very, you know,
# 等下就很柴
it would be very dry and hard.
# 搞點油的話
With some oil,
# 比較香
it smells better.
# 這生薑掉出來
The ginger is falling out.
# 把這個生薑
Let me put the ginger,
# 都放到它肚子裡面去
all into its belly.
# 按一下摩
Give it a massage.
# 腳上也給它按一下摩
The feet need a massage too.
# 再給它 腌個半個小時
We leave it, and marinate it for half an hour.
# 等個半個小時
After half an hour,
# 就上
We can,
# 就搞一根
I'll get a,
# 我就搞一根那個
I'll get a, you know,
# 竹子來 把它穿上
a bamboo stick. And then pierce it,
# 穿進去
pierce it through the chicken,
# 好 先讓它待在這裡上
Alright! Let's leave it here first.
# 待在這裡先啊
Stay here, alright?
# 別動
Don't move around.
# 聽話
Be a good chicken.
# 我去搞根竹子 把那火生起來
Let me fetch a bamboo stick, and set the fire.
# 然後再把它串起來 就可以直接烤啦
Then we fix it onto the stick and it can be grilled right away.
# 削一下就可以了
Trim it here, and it's done.
# 可以
Alright!
# 走 吃肉啦 走
Go! Let's have some meat! Go!
# 先把它串起來
Fix it onto the stick first.
# 這樣的話 順便把這裡也串住
Yea, good. Then I can get here fixed as well.
# 額 生薑全部掉出來了
Eh? The gingers have all fallen out.
# 不要了
Never mind
# 我它們腳來這裡
Put the feet here, and then,
# 綁起來
tie them up.
# 你看
Look!
# 把它綁起來啦
I've tied it up now.
# 綁的紥紥實實的
And I've tied it tight and firm.
# 就直接這樣烤
Then it can be grilled right away.
# 拿上面去
Let me take it up there.
# 狗 (註︰沒有原字幕)
Doggies!
# 有好吃的哦
I have some very good food here!
# 要不要過來哦
Are you guys coming with me?
# 這個火升起來了
So the fire has been set.
# 可以烤了
We can start grilling now.
# 誒呀 剛剛好哦
Aya! It fits.
# 好 這樣就可以
Alright! Everything is fine now.
# 給它起個名字 叫小胖熊
Let me give him a name. He's called Chubby Bear.
# 跟他那個胖
He's as fat as him.
# 要不要雞
Want some chicken?
# 不要
No, he doesn't.
# 搞個水車來
I should get a water wheel,
# 會動的
which can turn.
# 用這個葉子 做個刷子出來
Let me pick a leaf and make a brush.
# 用這個刷子刷點那個
With the brush, I can brush some, you know,
# 把它拿起來
Hold it high!
# 刷點這個油 才沒那麼幹
Brush some oil, so that it won't be too dry.
# 搞點油給它心上
Put some oil onto its heart.
# 心都看得到
I can see its heart.
# 這個雞瓜也放點油
I put some oil onto the feet as well.
# 轉了它才會
I turn and turn and turn, so that it,
# 才會
so that it,
# 才會暈了
so that it feels dizzy.
# 有點燒焦
It's a bit burnt.
# 狗熊在打架 (註︰沒有原字幕)
Chu, Chubby Bear is having a fight.
# 你看 現在很香了哦
Look! It smells really good now.
# 你看 再烤半個小時
Look! After half an hour,
# 不用烤半個小時
no, not half an hour,
# 烤多幾分鐘就可以
after a few minutes, I can,
# 把那個蜂蜜刷上去
I can start putting on the honey.
# 直接可以開吃啦
Then we can start our feast right away.
# 好靚
Beautiful!
# 差不多就要刷蜂蜜啦
It's almost time for the honey.
# 刷點蜂蜜
Put some honey.
# 你看這個蜂蜜
Have a look at this honey!
# 搞一點在它的 身上
I put some onto its, body.
# 會不會太多啦
Would it be too much?
# 沒事 甜一點好了
No worries. Let it be sweeter.
# 哎呀
Wa aya!
# 好香
It smells so good!
# 好啦好啦
Alright, alright!
# 好靚啊 你看
It's really beautiful! Look!
# 你看
Look!
# 這個
The,
# 這個 這個顔色
the, the colour...
# 好香 我吃一口 吃一口先
It smells great! I have a bite, have a bite first.
# 嗯~可以哦
Um~Not bad!
# 很香
It smells so good!
# 找個地方坐著來吃
Let me take a seat and enjoy it.
# 好 放在這裡先 先給它鬆綁
Alright. Put it here. Let me untie it first.
# 鬆綁
Untie it.
# 這個
The
# 這個腳
the foot,
# 燒糊啦
is burnt.
# 狗 (註︰沒有原字幕)
Doggies!
# 小狗
# 來 骨頭
C'mon! Bones!
# 都給狗
All for the dogs
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
The video ends here.
# 嗯 很結實的肉
Um! The texture is really firm.